PROFILE

I have been building web sites since the 1990s. My favourite framework is Django (Python) but I know from experience I can get the job done in ASP.NET, Drupal (PHP), Ruby on Rails or any number of other systems. I've done my fair share of application and system programming as well. I love beautiful, useful things, so I work hard on code quality and I appreciate good design and typography.

EDUCATION

BA Mathematics and Computation, first-class honours, Oxford 1986–1989

Web development and general programming on a variety of platforms including Dlango (Python), Ruby on Rails, Drupal (PHP), ASP.NET; frontend HTML, javaScript, and CSS; back-end Python, C++, Java, SQL, MongoDB, etc.

Semantic web & XML standards like RDF, SPAQL, XSLT, Relax NG, Atom.

I have a keen interest in web and print design.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DEVELOPER, SIEMENS MAY-JULY 2012

Added features to an internal code-review tool to help streamline their QA process.

DEVELOPER, OPTIMOR 2010–2012

One of a small development team, working on billmonitor.com with Scrum/Kanban and test-driven development practices.

- Got our billing-site web-crawlers (Python) to over 99% accuracy and success rates in the face of continually mutating and unreliable thirdparty sites.
- Created internal tools for tracking and prioritising accounts that needed manual intervention.
- On the Ruby on Rails front-end I designed and implemented a new deal page that doubled click-throughs to vendor sites overnight.
- Redesigned corporate site optimorlabs.com

SENIOR CONSULTANT, OXFORD COMPUTER CONSULTANTS 1995-2010

Bespoke software development for a variety of clients: user interfaces for data-logging systems (visualizations while gathering data, offline analysis), an IDE for a hardware compiler, and web application development. Depending on the project I might be writing architectural design documents and proposals or obsessing over details of CSS.

Here are some of the bigger projects from the last 5 years:

- **smarttraining.co.uk** (2009), a e-commerce web site in Drupal. New visual design, custom module in PHP for browsing and booking course. The new site launched in time for the Autumn rush.
- **diploma-support.org** (2008/09). Implemented in Drupal with custom theme and site-specific modules in PHP; customized SIMILE Timeline and the TinyMCE rich-text editor. We got a complex site running in six weeks, with new features added monthly after that. Set up group code reviews so we could share what we had learned each week.
- **REACT** (2007/08). A European R&D project developing intelligent interoperability between emergency services. Designed and built middleware for exchanging messages between existing command-and-control terminals and agents written by different consortium members in C# on .NET, Java J2EE, and other platforms. This remains as the backbone of the REACT system.
- Cognisco (2005–2008). Web applications (in ASP.NET) for creating and delivering competency assessments and training to large enterprises.
 Architected the new suite. Pushed unit tests and test-driven development. Designed & built user experience with Adobe Flash 8, DHTML, CSS. Nursed the customer's servers through the first 100,000-candidate deployment and advised on scalability.

DEPARTMENTAL LECTURER, OXFORD UNIVERSITY 1990–1995

Departmental lecturer, responsible for assisting Maths and Computation students with doing their practical work. Wrote introductory material for using the computers.

INTERESTS

Weekend programming projects and articles on *github.com/pdc* and *alleged.org.uk/pdc/*

Co-organizer of the small-press comics convention CAPTION since 1992, including the *caption.org* web site.